A - 10PTS
Your non-profit organization (iCORE - interntational Confederation of Revolver Enthusiasts) coordinates a very successful foreign student exchange program. Over the last few years, demand has sky-rocketed and now you need assistance with your task.
The program your organization runs works as follows: All candidates are asked for their original location and the location they would like to go to. The program works out only if every student has a suitable exchange partner. In other words, if a student wants to go from A to B, there must be another student who wants to go from B to A. This was an easy task when there were only about 50 candidates, however now there are up to 500000 candidates!
INPUT
The input file contains multiple cases. Each test case will consist of a line containing n – the number of candidates (1 ≤ n ≤ 500000), followed by n lines representing the exchange information for each candidate. Each of these lines will contain 2 integers, separated by a single space, representing the candidate’s original location and the candidate’s target location respectively. Locations will be represented by nonnegative integer numbers. You may assume that no candidate will have his or her original location being the same as his or her target location as this would fall into the domestic exchange program. The input is terminated by a case where n = 0; this case should not be processed.
OUTPUT
For each test case, print ‘YES’ on a single line if there is a way for the exchange program to work out, otherwise print ‘NO’.
SAMPLE INPUT
10
1 2
2 1
3 4
4 3
100 200
200 100
57 2
2 57
1 2
2 1
10
1 2
3 4
5 6
7 8
9 10
11 12
13 14
15 16
17 18
19 20
0
SAMPLE OUTPUT
YES
NO


B -  10PTS
Vova plans to go to the conference by train. Initially, the train is at the point 1 and the destination point of the path is the point L. The speed of the train is 1 length unit per minute (i.e. at the first minute the train is at the point 1, at the second minute — at the point 2 and so on).
There are lanterns on the path. They are placed at the points with coordinates divisible by v (i.e. the first lantern is at the point v, the second is at the point 2v and so on).
There is also exactly one standing train which occupies all the points from l to r inclusive.
Vova can see the lantern at the point p if p is divisible by v and there is no standing train at this position (p∉[l;r]). Thus, if the point with the lantern is one of the points covered by the standing train, Vova can't see this lantern.
Your problem is to say the number of lanterns Vova will see during the path. Vova plans to go to t different conferences, so you should answer t independent queries.
INPUT
The first line of the input contains one integer t (1≤t≤10^4) — the number of queries.
Then t lines follow. The i-th line contains four integers Li,vi,li,ri (1≤L,v≤10^9, 1≤l≤r≤L) — destination point of the i-th path, the period of the lantern appearance and the segment occupied by the standing train.
OUTPUT
Print t lines. The i-th line should contain one integer — the answer for the i-th query.
SAMPLE INPUT
5
10 2 3 7
100 51 51 51
1234 1 100 199
1000000000 1 1 1000000000
1000000000 1000000000 2 999999999
SAMPLE OUTPUT
3
0
1134
0
1


C - 10PTS
Vova's house is an array consisting of n elements (yeah, this is the first problem, I think, where someone lives in the array). There are heaters in some positions of the array. The i-th element of the array is 1 if there is a heater in the position i, otherwise the i-th element of the array is 0.
Each heater has a value r (r is the same for all heaters). This value means that the heater at the position pos can warm up all the elements in range [pos−r+1;pos+r−1].
Vova likes to walk through his house while he thinks, and he hates cold positions of his house. Vova wants to switch some of his heaters on in such a way that each element of his house will be warmed up by at least one heater.
Vova's target is to warm up the whole house (all the elements of the array), i.e. if n=6, r=2 and heaters are at positions 2 and 5, then Vova can warm up the whole house if he switches all the heaters in the house on (then the first 3 elements will be warmed up by the first heater and the last 3 elements will be warmed up by the second heater).
Initially, all the heaters are off.
But from the other hand, Vova didn't like to pay much for the electricity. So he wants to switch the minimum number of heaters on in such a way that each element of his house is warmed up by at least one heater.
Your task is to find this number of heaters or say that it is impossible to warm up the whole house.
INPUT
The first line of the input contains two integers n and r (1≤n,r≤1000) — the number of elements in the array and the value of heaters.
The second line contains n integers a1,a2,…,an (0≤ai≤1) — the Vova's house description.
OUTPUT
Print one integer — the minimum number of heaters needed to warm up the whole house or -1 if it is impossible to do it.
SAMPLE INPUT
6 2
0 1 1 0 0 1
SAMPLE OUTPUT
3
SAMPLE INPUT
5 3
1 0 0 0 1
SAMPLE OUTPUT
2
SAMPLE INPUT
10 3
0 0 1 1 0 1 0 0 0 1
SAMPLE OUTPUT
3
SAMPLE INPUT
5 10
0 0 0 0 0
SAMPLE OUTPUT
-1


D - 10PTS
You are given a string t consisting of n lowercase Latin letters and an integer number k.
Let's define a substring of some string s with indices from l to r as s[l…r].
Your task is to construct such string s of minimum possible length that there are exactly k positions i such that s[i…i+n−1]=t. In other words, your task is to construct such string s of minimum possible length that there are exactly k substrings of s equal to t.
It is guaranteed that the answer is always unique.
INPUT
The first line of the input contains two integers n and k (1≤n,k≤50) — the length of the string t and the number of substrings.
The second line of the input contains the string t consisting of exactly n lowercase Latin letters.
OUTPUT
Print such string s of minimum possible length that there are exactly k substrings of s equal to t.
It is guaranteed that the answer is always unique.
SAMPLE INPUT
3 4
aba
SAMPLE OUTPUT
ababababa
SAMPLE INPUT
3 2
cat
SAMPLE OUTPUT
catcat


E - 10PTS
You are given a problemset consisting of n problems. The difficulty of the i-th problem is ai. It is guaranteed that all difficulties are distinct and are given in the increasing order.
You have to assemble the contest which consists of some problems of the given problemset. In other words, the contest you have to assemble should be a subset of problems (not necessary consecutive) of the given problemset. There is only one condition that should be satisfied: for each problem but the hardest one (the problem with the maximum difficulty) there should be a problem with the difficulty greater than the difficulty of this problem but not greater than twice the difficulty of this problem. In other words, let ai1,ai2,…,aip be the difficulties of the selected problems in increasing order. Then for each j from 1 to p−1 aij+1≤aij*2 should hold. It means that the contest consisting of only one problem is always valid.
Among all contests satisfying the condition above you have to assemble one with the maximum number of problems. Your task is to find this number of problems.
INPUT
The first line of the input contains one integer n (1≤n≤2⋅105) — the number of problems in the problemset.
The second line of the input contains n integers a1,a2,…,an (1≤ai≤109) — difficulties of the problems. It is guaranteed that difficulties of the problems are distinct and are given in the increasing order.
OUTPUT
Print a single integer — maximum number of problems in the contest satisfying the condition in the problem statement.
SAMPLE INPUT
10
1 2 5 6 7 10 21 23 24 49
SAMPLE OUTPUT
4
SAMPLE INPUT
5
2 10 50 110 250
SAMPLE OUTPUT
1
SAMPLE INPUT
6
4 7 12 100 150 199
SAMPLE OUTPUT
3


F - 10PTS
Polycarpus has a ribbon, its length is n. He wants to cut the ribbon in a way that fulfils the following two conditions:
 -After the cutting each ribbon piece should have length a, b or c.
 -After the cutting the number of ribbon pieces should be maximum.
Help Polycarpus and find the number of ribbon pieces after the required cutting.
INPUT
The first line contains four space-separated integers n, a, b and c (1 ≤ n, a, b, c ≤ 4000) — the length of the original ribbon and the acceptable lengths of the ribbon pieces after the cutting, correspondingly. The numbers a, b and c can coincide.
OUTPUT
Print a single number — the maximum possible number of ribbon pieces. It is guaranteed that at least one correct ribbon cutting exists.
SAMPLE INPUT
5 5 3 2
SAMPLE OUTPUT
2
SAMPLE INPUT
7 5 5 2
SAMPLE OUTPUT
2


G - 10PTS
You have two positive integers w and h. Your task is to count the number of rhombi which have the following properties:
 -Have positive area.
 -With vertices at integer points.
 -All vertices of the rhombi are located inside or on the border of the rectangle with vertices at points (0, 0), (w, 0), (w, h), (0, h). In other words, for all vertices (xi, yi) of the rhombus the following conditions should fulfill: 0 ≤ xi ≤ w and 0 ≤ yi ≤ h.
 -Its diagonals are parallel to the axis.
Count the number of such rhombi.
Let us remind you that a rhombus is a quadrilateral whose four sides all have the same length.
INPUT
The first line contains two integers w and h (1 ≤ w, h ≤ 4000) — the rectangle's sizes.
OUTPUT
Print a single number — the number of sought rhombi.
SAMPLE INPUT
2
SAMPLE OUTPUT
1
SAMPLE INPUT
1 2
SAMPLE OUTPUT
0


H - 10PTS
The Association of Chess Monsters (ACM) is planning their annual team match up against the rest of the world. The match will be on 30 boards, with 15 players playing white and 15 players playing black. ACM has many players to choose from, and they try to pick the best team they can. The ability of each player for playing white is measured on a scale from 1 to 100 and the same for playing black. During the match a player can play white or black but not both. The value of a team is the total of players' abilities to play white for players designated to play white and players' abilities to play black for players designated to play black. ACM wants to pick up a team with the highest total value.
INPUT
Input consists of a sequence of lines giving players' abilities. Each line gives the abilities of a single player by two integer numbers separated by a single space. The first number is the player's ability to play white and the second is the player's ability to play black. There will be no less than 30 and no more than 1000 lines on input.
OUTPUT
Output a single line containing an integer number giving the value of the best chess team that ACM can assemble.
SAMPLE 
INPUT
87 84
66 78
86 94
93 87
72 100
78 63
60 91
77 64
77 91
87 73
69 62
80 68
81 83
74 63
86 68
53 80
59 73
68 70
57 94
93 62
74 80
70 72
88 85
75 99
71 66
77 64
81 92
74 57
71 63
82 97
76 56
OUTPUT
2506


I - 10PTS
Canada has a multi-party system of government. Each candidate is generally associated with a party, and the party whose candidates win the most ridings generally forms the government. Some candidates run as independents, meaning they are not associated with any party. Your job is to count the votes for a particular riding and to determine the party with which the winning candidate is associated.
INPUT
The first line of input contains a positive integer n satisfying 2 <= n <= 20, the number of candidates in the riding. n pairs of lines follow: the first line in each pair is the name of the candidate, up to 80 characters; the second line is the name of the party, up to 80 characters, or the word "independent" if the candidate has no party. No candidate name is repeated and no party name is repeated in the input. No lines contain leading or trailing blanks. 
The next line contains a positive integer m <= 10000, and is followed by m lines each indicating the name of a candidate for which a ballot is cast. Any names not in the list of candidates should be ignored.
OUTPUT
Output consists of a single line containing one of: 
 -The name of the party with whom the winning candidate is associated, if there is a winning candidate and that candidate is associated with a party. 
 -The word "independent" if there is a winning candidate and that candidate is not associated with a party. 
 -The word "tie" if there is no winner; that is, if no candidate receives more votes than every other candidate.
SAMPLE
INPUT
3
Marilyn Manson
Rhinoceros
Jane Doe
Family Coalition
John Smith
independent
6
John Smith
Marilyn Manson
Marilyn Manson
Jane Doe
John Smith
Marilyn Manson
OUTPUT
Rhinoceros


J - 10PTS
Once upon a time in a country far away lived a king and he had a big kingdom. He was a very clever king but he had one weakness -- he could count only up to three. 
Nevertheless, he did not consider this to be a really great drawback, since he had a lot of wizards who could count up to one hundred (and some of them, people said, even up to one thousand), so it was all right. But one day the grief came to the kingdom as the outnumbering barbarians started to approach from all sides. And the king then had to make the most important decision in his life. He had to choose which of his sons to make generals that he would send to the borders of the country to lead the army. 
However, the king knew that though some of his sons were clever, just like he was, some of them were quite stupid and could only lower army spirits with their wrong decisions. More precisely, he knew about each of his sons his mental potential -- an integer number ranging from minus three to three (remember, that the king could count only up to three). He also knew that the chance of his army defeating barbarians was proportional to the sum of some powers of mental potentials of those of his sons that he would make generals (the power exponent was a positive integer number, the same for all his sons and not exceeding three either). Thus he had to choose such a combination of his sons to lead 
the army, that this sum would be maximal possible. 
However, the king himself could not make all apropriate calculations since, for example, the second power of the number not exceeding three (which is its square) could be greater than three, and therefore he asked you, his most intellegent wizard, to solve this problem.
INPUT
The first line of the input file contains the number of the sons of the king (integer number less or equal to one hundred). The second line contains the positive integer number not exceeding three, the exponent in the formula used to calculate the chance of defeating barbarians. The third line contains the list of mental potentials of king’s sons -- all integer numbers, not greater than three by their absolute value.
OUTPUT
Output the only number -- the maximal possible chance of defeating barbarians measured as the sum described.
SAMPLE
INPUT
3
3
2 -1 1
OUTPUT
9


K - 15PTS
Happy PMP is freshman and he is learning about algorithmic problems. He enjoys playing algorithmic games a lot.
One of the seniors gave Happy PMP a nice game. He is given two permutations of numbers 1 through n and is asked to convert the first one to the second. In one move he can remove the last number from the permutation of numbers and inserts it back in an arbitrary position. He can either insert last number between any two consecutive numbers, or he can place it at the beginning of the permutation.
Happy PMP has an algorithm that solves the problem. But it is not fast enough. He wants to know the minimum number of moves to convert the first permutation to the second.
INPUT
The first line contains a single integer n (1 ≤ n ≤ 2*10^5) — the quantity of the numbers in the both given permutations.
Next line contains n space-separated integers — the first permutation. Each number between 1 to n will appear in the permutation exactly once.
Next line describe the second permutation in the same format.
OUTPUT
Print a single integer denoting the minimum number of moves required to convert the first permutation to the second.
SAMPLE INPUT
3
3 2 1
1 2 3
SAMPLE OUTPUT
2
SAMPLE INPUT
5
1 2 3 4 5
1 5 2 3 4
SAMPLE OUTPUT
1
SAMPLE INPUT
5
1 5 2 3 4
1 2 3 4 5
SAMPLE OUTPUT
3


L - 15PTS
There is a new revolution in the parking lot business: the parking tower. The concept is simple: you drive your car into the elevator at the entrance of the tower, and the elevator and conveyor belts drag the car to an empty parking spot, where the car remains until you pick it up. When you return, the elevator and conveyor belts move your car back to the entrance and you’re done.
The layout of the tower is simple. There is one central elevator that transports the cars between the different floors. On each floor there is one giant circular conveyor belt on which the cars stand. This belt can move in clockwise and counterclockwise direction. When the elevator arrives on a floor, it becomes part of the belt so that cars can move through it.
At the end of the day the tower is usually packed with cars and a lot of people come to pick them up. Customers are processed in a first come first serve order: the elevator is moved to the floor of the first car, the conveyor belt moves the car on the elevator, the elevator is moved down again, and so on. We like to know how long it takes before the last customer gets his car. Moving the elevator one floor up- or downwards takes 10 seconds and moving a conveyor belt one car in either direction takes 5 seconds.
INPUT
On the first line one positive number: the number of testcases, at most 100. After that per testcase:
 -One line with two integers h and l with 1 ≤ h ≤ 50 and 2 ≤ l ≤ 50: the height of the parking tower and the length of the conveyor belts.
 -h lines with l integers: the initial placement of the cars. The jth number on the ith line describes the jth position on the ith floor. This number is −1 if the position is empty, and r if the position is occupied by the rth car to pick up. The positive numbers form a consecutive sequence from 1 to the number of cars. The entrance is on the first floor and the elevator (which is initially empty) is in the first position. There is at least one car in the parking tower.
OUTPUT
Per testcase:
 -One line with the number of seconds before the last customer is served.
SAMPLE
INPUT
2
1 5
-1 2 1 -1 3
3 6
-1 5 6 -1 -1 3
-1 -1 7 -1 2 9
-1 10 4 1 8 -1
OUTPUT
25
320


M - 15PTS
In this problem, we consider a simple programming language that has only declarations of one-dimensional integer arrays and assignment statements. The problem is to find a bug in the given program.
The syntax of this language is given in BNF as follows:
‹program›	::=	‹declaration› | ‹program›‹declaration› | ‹program›‹assignment›
‹declaration›	::=	‹array_name›[‹number›]‹new_line›
‹assignment›	::=	‹array_name›[‹expression›]=‹expression›‹new_line›
‹expression›	::=	‹number› | ‹array_name›[‹expression›]
‹number›	::=	‹digit› | ‹digit_positive›‹digit_string›
‹digit_string›	::=	‹digit› | ‹digit›‹digit_string›
‹digit_positive›	::=	1 | 2 | 3 | 4 | 5 | 6 | 7 | 8 | 9
‹digit›	::=	0 | ‹digit_positive›
‹array_name›	::=	a | b | c | d | e | f | g | h | i | j | k | l | m |
                        n | o | p | q | r | s | t | u | v | w | x | y | z |
                        A | B | C | D | E | F | G | H | I | J | K | L | M |
                        N | O | P | Q | R | S | T | U | V | W | X | Y | Z
where ‹new_line› denotes a new line character (LF).
Characters used in a program are alphabetical letters, decimal digits, =, [, ] and new line characters. No other characters appear in a program.
A declaration declares an array and specifies its length. Valid indices of an array of length n are integers between 0 and n − 1, inclusive. Note that the array names are case sensitive, i.e. array a and array A are different arrays. The initial value of each element in the declared array is undefined.
For example, array a of length 10 and array b of length 5 are declared respectively as follows.
a[10]
b[5]
An expression evaluates to a non-negative integer. A ‹number› is interpreted as a decimal integer. An ‹array_name›[‹expression›] evaluates to the value of the ‹expression›-th element of the array. An assignment assigns the value denoted by the right hand side to the array element specified by the left hand side.
Examples of assignments are as follows.
a[0]=3
a[1]=0
a[2]=a[a[1]]
a[a[0]]=a[1]
A program is executed from the first line, line by line. You can assume that an array is declared once and only once before any of its element is assigned or referred to.
Given a program, you are requested to find the following bugs.
 -An index of an array is invalid.
 -An array element that has not been assigned before is referred to in an assignment as an index of array or as the value to be assigned.
You can assume that other bugs, such as syntax errors, do not appear. You can also assume that integers represented by ‹number›s are between 0 and 2^31 − 1 (= 2147483647), inclusive.
INPUT
The input consists of multiple datasets followed by a line which contains only a single ‘.’ (period). Each dataset consists of a program also followed by a line which contains only a single ‘.’ (period). A program does not exceed 1000 lines. Any line does not exceed 80 characters excluding a new line character.
OUTPUT
For each program in the input, you should answer the line number of the assignment in which the first bug appears. The line numbers start with 1 for each program. If the program does not have a bug, you should answer zero. The output should not contain extra characters such as spaces.
SAMPLE
INPUT
a[3]
a[0]=a[1]
.
x[1]
x[0]=x[0]
.
a[0]
a[0]=1
.
b[2]
b[0]=2
b[1]=b[b[0]]
b[0]=b[1]
.
g[2]
G[10]
g[0]=0
g[1]=G[0]
.
a[2147483647]
a[0]=1
B[2]
B[a[0]]=2
a[B[a[0]]]=3
a[2147483646]=a[2]
.
.
OUTPUT
2
2
2
3
4
0


N - 15PTS
Vasya likes taking part in Codeforces contests. When a round is over, Vasya follows all submissions in the system testing tab.
There are n solutions, the i-th of them should be tested on ai tests, testing one solution on one test takes 1 second. The solutions are judged in the order from 1 to n. There are k testing processes which test solutions simultaneously. Each of them can test at most one solution at a time.
At any time moment t when some testing process is not judging any solution, it takes the first solution from the queue and tests it on each test in increasing order of the test ids. Let this solution have id i, then it is being tested on the first test from time moment t till time moment t+1, then on the second test till time moment t+2 and so on. This solution is fully tested at time moment t+ai, and after that the testing process immediately starts testing another solution.
Consider some time moment, let there be exactly m fully tested solutions by this moment. There is a caption "System testing: d%" on the page with solutions, where d is calculated as
d = round(100 * m / n),
where round(x)=⌊x+0.5⌋ is a function which maps every real to the nearest integer.
Vasya calls a submission interesting if there is a time moment (possibly, non-integer) when the solution is being tested on some test q, and the caption says "System testing: q%". Find the number of interesting solutions.
Please note that in case when multiple processes attempt to take the first submission from the queue at the same moment (for instance, at the initial moment), the order they take the solutions does not matter.
INPUT
The first line contains two positive integers n and k (1≤n≤1000, 1≤k≤100) standing for the number of submissions and the number of testing processes respectively.
The second line contains n positive integers a1,a2,…,an (1≤ai≤150), where ai is equal to the number of tests the i-th submission is to be run on.
OUTPUT
Output the only integer — the number of interesting submissions.
SAMPLE INPUT
2 2
49 100
SAMPLE OUTPUT
1
SAMPLE INPUT
4 2
32 100 33 1
SAMPLE OUTPUT
2
SAMPLE INPUT
14 5
48 19 6 9 50 20 3 42 38 43 36 21 44 6
SAMPLE OUTPUT
5


O - 15PTS
At the first holiday in spring, the town Shortriver traditionally conducts a flower festival. Townsfolk wear traditional wreaths during these festivals. Each wreath contains exactly k flowers.
The work material for the wreaths for all n citizens of Shortriver is cut from the longest flowered liana that grew in the town that year. Liana is a sequence a1, a2, ..., am, where ai is an integer that denotes the type of flower at the position i. This year the liana is very long (m≥n*k), and that means every citizen will get a wreath.
Very soon the liana will be inserted into a special cutting machine in order to make work material for wreaths. The machine works in a simple manner: it cuts k flowers from the beginning of the liana, then another k flowers and so on. Each such piece of k flowers is called a workpiece. The machine works until there are less than k flowers on the liana.
Diana has found a weaving schematic for the most beautiful wreath imaginable. In order to weave it, k flowers must contain flowers of types b1, b2, ..., bs, while other can be of any type. If a type appears in this sequence several times, there should be at least that many flowers of that type as the number of occurrences of this flower in the sequence. The order of the flowers in a workpiece does not matter.
Diana has a chance to remove some flowers from the liana before it is inserted into the cutting machine. She can remove flowers from any part of the liana without breaking liana into pieces. If Diana removes too many flowers, it may happen so that some of the citizens do not get a wreath. Could some flowers be removed from the liana so that at least one workpiece would conform to the schematic and machine would still be able to create at least n workpieces?
INPUT
The first line contains four integers m, k, n and s (1≤n,k,m≤5*10^5, k*n≤m, 1≤s≤k): the number of flowers on the liana, the number of flowers in one wreath, the amount of citizens and the length of Diana's flower sequence respectively.
The second line contains m integers a1, a2, ..., am (1≤ai≤5*10^5)  — types of flowers on the liana.
The third line contains s integers b1, b2, ..., bs (1≤bi≤5*10^5)  — the sequence in Diana's schematic.
OUTPUT
If it's impossible to remove some of the flowers so that there would be at least n workpieces and at least one of them fullfills Diana's schematic requirements, output −1.
Otherwise in the first line output one integer d  — the number of flowers to be removed by Diana.
In the next line output d different integers  — the positions of the flowers to be removed.
If there are multiple answers, print any.
SAMPLE INPUT
7 3 2 2
1 2 3 3 2 1 2
2 2
SAMPLE OUTPUT
1
4
SAMPLE INPUT
13 4 3 3
3 2 6 4 1 4 4 7 1 3 3 2 4
4 3 4
SAMPLE OUTPUT
-1
SAMPLE INPUT
13 4 1 3
3 2 6 4 1 4 4 7 1 3 3 2 4
4 3 4
SAMPLE OUTPUT
9
1 2 3 4 5 9 11 12 13


Q - 15PTS
Cowboy Vlad has a birthday today! There are n children who came to the celebration. In order to greet Vlad, the children decided to form a circle around him. Among the children who came, there are both tall and low, so if they stand in a circle arbitrarily, it may turn out, that there is a tall and low child standing next to each other, and it will be difficult for them to hold hands. Therefore, children want to stand in a circle so that the maximum difference between the growth of two neighboring children would be minimal possible.
Formally, let's number children from 1 to n in a circle order, that is, for every i child with number i will stand next to the child with number i+1, also the child with number 1 stands next to the child with number n. Then we will call the discomfort of the circle the maximum absolute difference of heights of the children, who stand next to each other.
Please help children to find out how they should reorder themselves, so that the resulting discomfort is smallest possible.
INPUT
The first line contains a single integer n (2≤n≤100) — the number of the children who came to the cowboy Vlad's birthday.
The second line contains integers a1,a2,…,an (1≤ai≤10^9) denoting heights of every child.
OUTPUT
Print exactly n integers — heights of the children in the order in which they should stand in a circle. You can start printing a circle with any child.
If there are multiple possible answers, print any of them.
SAMPLE INPUT
5
2 1 1 3 2
SAMPLE OUTPUT
1 2 3 2 1
SAMPLE INPUT
3
30 10 20
SAMPLE OUTPUT
10 20 30


R - 15PTS
Mr. Apple, a gourmet, works as editor-in-chief of a gastronomic periodical. He travels around the world, tasting new delights of famous chefs from the most fashionable restaurants. Mr. Apple has his own signature method of review  — in each restaurant Mr. Apple orders two sets of dishes on two different days. All the dishes are different, because Mr. Apple doesn't like to eat the same food. For each pair of dishes from different days he remembers exactly which was better, or that they were of the same quality. After this the gourmet evaluates each dish with a positive integer.
Once, during a revision of a restaurant of Celtic medieval cuisine named «Poisson», that serves chestnut soup with fir, warm soda bread, spicy lemon pie and other folk food, Mr. Apple was very pleasantly surprised the gourmet with its variety of menu, and hence ordered too much. Now he's confused about evaluating dishes.
The gourmet tasted a set of n dishes on the first day and a set of m dishes on the second day. He made a table a of size n×m, in which he described his impressions. If, according to the expert, dish i from the first set was better than dish j from the second set, then aij is equal to ">", in the opposite case aij is equal to "<". Dishes also may be equally good, in this case aij is "=".
Now Mr. Apple wants you to help him to evaluate every dish. Since Mr. Apple is very strict, he will evaluate the dishes so that the maximal number used is as small as possible. But Mr. Apple also is very fair, so he never evaluates the dishes so that it goes against his feelings. In other words, if aij is "<", then the number assigned to dish i from the first set should be less than the number of dish j from the second set, if aij is ">", then it should be greater, and finally if aij is "=", then the numbers should be the same.
Help Mr. Apple to evaluate each dish from both sets so that it is consistent with his feelings, or determine that this is impossible.
INPUT
The first line contains integers n and m (1≤n,m≤1000) — the number of dishes in both days.
Each of the next n lines contains a string of m symbols. The j-th symbol on i-th line is aij. All strings consist only of "<", ">" and "=".
OUTPUT
The first line of output should contain "Yes", if it's possible to do a correct evaluation for all the dishes, or "No" otherwise.
If case an answer exist, on the second line print n integers — evaluations of dishes from the first set, and on the third line print m integers — evaluations of dishes from the second set.
SAMPLE INPUT
3 4
>>>>
>>>>
>>>>
SAMPLE OUTPUT
Yes
2 2 2 
1 1 1 1
SAMPLE INPUT
3 3
>>>
<<<
>>>
SAMPLE OUTPUT
Yes
3 1 3 
2 2 2

SAMPLE INPUT
3 2
==
=<
==
SAMPLE OUTPUT
NO


S - 15PTS
JATC loves Banh-mi (a Vietnamese food). His affection for Banh-mi is so much that he always has it for breakfast. This morning, as usual, he buys a Banh-mi and decides to enjoy it in a special way.
First, he splits the Banh-mi into n parts, places them on a row and numbers them from 1 through n. For each part i, he defines the deliciousness of the part as xi∈{0,1}. JATC's going to eat those parts one by one. At each step, he chooses arbitrary remaining part and eats it. Suppose that part is the i-th part then his enjoyment of the Banh-mi will increase by xi and the deliciousness of all the remaining parts will also increase by xi. The initial enjoyment of JATC is equal to 0.
For example, suppose the deliciousness of 3 parts are [0,1,0]. If JATC eats the second part then his enjoyment will become 1 and the deliciousness of remaining parts will become [1,_,1]. Next, if he eats the first part then his enjoyment will become 2 and the remaining parts will become [_,_,2]. After eating the last part, JATC's enjoyment will become 4.
However, JATC doesn't want to eat all the parts but to save some for later. He gives you q queries, each of them consisting of two integers li and ri. For each query, you have to let him know what is the maximum enjoyment he can get if he eats all the parts with indices in the range [li,ri] in some order.
All the queries are independent of each other. Since the answer to the query could be very large, print it modulo 10^9+7.
INPUT
The first line contains two integers n and q (1≤n,q≤100000).
The second line contains a string of n characters, each character is either '0' or '1'. The i-th character defines the deliciousness of the i-th part.
Each of the following q lines contains two integers li and ri (1≤li≤ri≤n) — the segment of the corresponding query.
OUTPUT
Print q lines, where i-th of them contains a single integer — the answer to the i-th query modulo 10^9+7.
SAMPLE INPUT
4 2
1011
1 4
3 4
SAMPLE OUTPUT
14
3
SAMPLE INPUT
3 2
111
1 2
3 3
SAMPLE OUTPUT
3
1


T - 15PTS
You are given a positive integer n greater or equal to 2. For every pair of integers a and b (2≤|a|,|b|≤n), you can transform a into b if and only if there exists an integer x such that 1<|x| and (a⋅x=b or b⋅x=a), where |x| denotes the absolute value of x.
After such a transformation, your score increases by |x| points and you are not allowed to transform a into b nor b into a anymore.
Initially, you have a score of 0. You can start at any integer and transform it as many times as you like. What is the maximum score you can achieve?
INPUT
A single line contains a single integer n (2≤n≤100000) — the given integer described above.
OUTPUT
Print an only integer — the maximum score that can be achieved with the transformations. If it is not possible to perform even a single transformation for all possible starting integers, print 0.
SAMPLE INPUT
4
SAMPLE OUTPUT
8
SAMPLE INPUT
6
SAMPLE OUTPUT
28
SAMPLE INPUT
2
SAMPLE OUTPUT
0


U - 20PTS
PMP is getting a warrior. He is practicing a lot, but the results are not acceptable yet. This time instead of programming contests, he decided to compete in a car racing to increase the spirit of victory. He decides to choose a competition that also exhibits algorithmic features.
AlgoRace is a special league of car racing where different teams compete in a country of n cities. Cities are numbered 1 through n. Every two distinct cities in the country are connected with one bidirectional road. Each competing team should introduce one driver and a set of cars.
The competition is held in r rounds. In i-th round, drivers will start at city si and finish at city ti. Drivers are allowed to change their cars at most ki times. Changing cars can take place in any city in no time. One car can be used multiple times in one round, but total number of changes should not exceed ki. Drivers can freely choose their path to destination.
PMP has prepared m type of purpose-built cars. Beside for PMP’s driving skills, depending on properties of the car and the road, a car traverses each road in each direction in different times.
PMP Warriors wants to devise best strategies of choosing car and roads in each round to maximize the chance of winning the cup. For each round they want to find the minimum time required to finish it.
INPUT
The first line contains three space-separated integers n, m, r (2 ≤ n ≤ 60, 1 ≤ m ≤ 60, 1 ≤ r ≤ 10^5) — the number of cities, the number of different types of cars and the number of rounds in the competition, correspondingly.
Next m sets of n × n matrices of integers between 0 to 106 (inclusive) will follow — describing the time one car requires to traverse different roads. The k-th integer in j-th line of the i-th set is the time that i-th car requires to traverse the road from j-th city to k-th city. These matrices are not necessarily symmetric, but their diagonal is always zero.
Next r lines contain description of the rounds. The i-th of these lines contains space-separated integers si, ti, ki (1 ≤ si, ti ≤ n, si ≠ ti, 0 ≤ ki ≤ 1000) — the number of starting city, finishing city and the number of possible car changes in i-th round, correspondingly.
OUTPUT
For each round you should print the minimum required time to complete the round in a single line.
SAMPLE INPUT
4 2 3
0 1 5 6
2 0 3 6
1 3 0 1
6 6 7 0
0 3 5 6
2 0 1 6
1 3 0 2
6 6 7 0
1 4 2
1 4 1
1 4 3
SAMPLE OUTPUT
3
4
3
SAMPLE INPUT
4 2 3
0 7 3 3
8 0 10 5
1 1 0 4
8 9 2 0
0 3 3 9
7 0 4 9
3 8 0 4
4 8 9 0
2 3 3
2 1 3
1 2 2
SAMPLE OUTPUT
4
5
3


V - 20PTS
Zart PMP is qualified for ICPC World Finals in Harbin, China. After team excursion to Sun Island Park for snow sculpture art exposition, PMP should get back to buses before they leave. But the park is really big and he does not know how to find them.
The park has n intersections numbered 1 through n. There are m bidirectional roads that connect some pairs of these intersections. At k intersections, ICPC volunteers are helping the teams and showing them the way to their destinations. Locations of volunteers are fixed and distinct.
When PMP asks a volunteer the way to bus station, he/she can tell him the whole path. But the park is fully covered with ice and snow and everywhere looks almost the same. So PMP can only memorize at most q intersections after each question (excluding the intersection they are currently standing). He always tells volunteers about his weak memory and if there is no direct path of length (in number of roads) at most q that leads to bus station, the volunteer will guide PMP to another volunteer (who is at most q intersections away, of course). ICPC volunteers know the area very well and always tell PMP the best way. So if there exists a way to bus stations, PMP will definitely find it.
PMP's initial location is intersection s and the buses are at intersection t. There will always be a volunteer at intersection s. Your job is to find out the minimum q which guarantees that PMP can find the buses.
INPUT
The first line contains three space-separated integers n, m, k (2 ≤ n ≤ 105, 0 ≤ m ≤ 2·105, 1 ≤ k ≤ n) — the number of intersections, roads and volunteers, respectively. Next line contains k distinct space-separated integers between 1 and n inclusive — the numbers of cities where volunteers are located.
Next m lines describe the roads. The i-th of these lines contains two space-separated integers ui, vi (1 ≤ ui, vi ≤ n, ui ≠ vi) — two intersections that i-th road connects. There will be at most one road between any two intersections.
Last line of input contains two space-separated integers s, t (1 ≤ s, t ≤ n, s ≠ t) — the initial location of PMP and the location of the buses. It might not always be possible to reach t from s.
It is guaranteed that there is always a volunteer at intersection s.
OUTPUT
Print on the only line the answer to the problem — the minimum value of q which guarantees that PMP can find the buses. If PMP cannot reach the buses at all, output -1 instead.
SAMPLE INPUT
6 6 3
1 3 6
1 2
2 3
4 2
5 6
4 5
3 4
1 6
SAMPLE OUTPUT
3
SAMPLE INPUT
6 5 3
1 5 6
1 2
2 3
3 4
4 5
6 3
1 5
SAMPLE OUTPUT
3


X- 20PTS
In one of his notebooks, Euclid gave a complex procedure for solving the following problem. With computers, perhaps there is an easier way. 
In a 2D plane, consider a line segment AB, another point C which is not collinear with AB, and a triangle DEF. The goal is to find points G and H such that: 
H is on the ray AC (it may be closer to A than C or further away, but angle CAB is the same as angle HAB) 
ABGH is a parallelogram (AB is parallel to HG, AH is parallel to BG) 
The area of parallelogram ABGH is the same as the area of triangle DEF 
INPUT
There will be several test cases. Each test case will consist of twelve real numbers, with no more than 3 decimal places each, on a single line. Those numbers will represent, in order: 
AX AY BX BY CX CY DX DY EX EY FX FY 
where point A is (AX,AY), point B is (BX,BY), and so on. Points A, B and C are guaranteed to NOT be collinear. Likewise, D, E and F are also guaranteed to be non-collinear. Every number is guaranteed to be in the range from -1000.0 to 1000.0 inclusive. End of the input will be signified by a line with twelve 0.0's.
OUTPUT
For each test case, print a single line with four decimal numbers. These represent points G and H, like this: 
GX GY HX HY 
where point G is (GX,GY) and point H is (HX,HY). Print all values rounded to 3 decimal places of precision (NOT truncated). Print a single space between numbers. Do not print any blank lines between answers.
SAMPLE
INPUT
0 0 5 0 0 5 3 2 7 2 0 4
1.3 2.6 12.1 4.5 8.1 13.7 2.2 0.1 9.8 6.6 1.9 6.7
0.0 0.0 0.0 0.0 0.0 0.0 0.0 0.0 0.0 0.0 0.0 0.0
OUTPUT
5.000 0.800 0.000 0.800
13.756 7.204 2.956 5.304


