BIG CLOCK - 10PTS
Our vicar raised money to have the church clock repaired for several weeks. The big clock, which used to strike the hours days and nights, was damaged several weeks ago and had been silent since then. 
After the clock was repaired, it works all right, but there is still something wrong with it: the clock will strike thirteen times at one o’clock, fourteen times at two o’clock... 24 times at 12:00, 1 time at 13:00... 
How many times will it strike now?
INPUT
The first line consists of only one integer T (T <= 30), representing the number of test cases. Then T cases follow. 
Each test case consists of only one line, representing the time now. Each line includes 2 integers H, M separated by a symbol ":". (0 <= H < 24, 0 <= M < 60)
OUTPUT
For each test case, output the answer in one line.
SAMPLE INPUT
3
1:00
01:01
00:00
SAMPLE OUTPUT
13
0
12

01000001 - 10PTS
Adding binary numbers is a very simple task, and very similar to the longhand addition of decimal numbers. As with decimal numbers, you start by adding the bits (digits) one column at a time, from right to left. Unlike decimal addition, there is little to memorize in the way of rules for the addition of binary bits:

   0 + 0 = 0
   1 + 0 = 1
   0 + 1 = 1
   1 + 1 = 10
   1 + 1 + 1 = 11
Just as with decimal addition, when the sum in one column is a two-bit (two-digit) number, the least significant figure is written as part of the total sum and the most significant figure is “carried” to the next left column. Consider the following examples:

                       11  1 <-- Carry bits --> 1   11
  1001101             1001001                    1000111
+ 0010010           + 0011001                  + 1010110
 --------           ---------                  ---------
  1011111             1100010                   10011101
The addition problem on the left did not require any bits to be carried, since the sum of bits in each column was either 1 or 0, not 10 or 11. In the other two problems, there definitely were bits to be carried, but the process of addition is still quite simple.
INPUT
The first line of input contains an integer N, ( 1 ≤ N ≤ 1000), which is the number of binary addition problems that follow. Each problem appears on a single line containing two binary values separated by a single space character. The maximum length of each binary value is 80 bits (binary digits). Note: The maximum length result could be 81 bits (binary digits).
OUTPUT
For each binary addition problem, print the problem number, a space, and the binary result of the addition. Extra leading zeroes must be omitted.
SAMPLE INPUT
3
1001101 10010
1001001 11001
1000111 1010110
SAMPLE OUTPUT
1 1011111
2 1100010
3 10011101

THE BANK OF KALII - 10PTS
Customers of the Bank of Kalii handle their banking transactions similar to the way they handle their taxes: be as terse as possible. As a result, when a customer writes a check or fills out a deposit or withdrawal form, they leave off the year on any date they write down. So, instead of writing: 09/20/2005, they would write: 9/20 and be done with it. In general, the year can be inferred since it will be relatively close to the date the transaction is actually processed by the bank.
Without going into the intricate details of how the Bank of Kalii calculates interest and banking fees (that is a problem for another time...), suffice to say the bank must determine the actual date the customer wrote on the check or form, and calculate the number of days prior (or in the future) the document is dated. You see, Kaliian bankers, like their government officials, are overworked, so they may not get around to processing transactions for up to a week. The customers know this, so they often date their checks and forms a several days in the future - this complicates the bankers' duties as well.
Your job is to write a program to compare a date written on a check or form with the date the transaction is being processed, and, determine the full date the customer meant as well as how many days prior (or in the future) the document is dated.
INPUT
The first line of input contains an integer N which is the number of datasets that follow (1 ≤ N ≤ 1000). Each dataset consists of a single line containing two dates: the transaction date and the document date; there is a single space between them. The transaction date is of the form M/D/Y where M is the month number (1 ≤ M ≤ 12), D is the day of month (1 ≤ D ≤ md1) and Y is the year (2000 ≤ Y ≤ 2200). The document date is of the form m/d where m is the month number (1 ≤ m ≤ 12) and d is the day of month (1 ≤ d ≤ md2). The values of md1 and md2 will not exceed the number of days in the respective months M and m.
OUTPUT
For each dataset print out the dataset number followed by a space followed by the result of the date comparison as shown in the table below: 

Result to print	Criteria
m/d/y IS n DAY(S) PRIOR	If the document date occurs before the
transaction date and is within 7 days in the past
m/d/y IS n DAY(S) AFTER	If the document date occurs after the transaction
date and is within 7 days in the future
SAME DAY	If the dates are the same.
OUT OF RANGE	All other results not with +/− 7 days.
SAMPLE INPUT
7
11/20/2005 11/21
11/20/2005 11/17
11/20/2005 11/20
11/20/2005 11/13
11/20/2005 11/28
1/2/2005 12/30
12/31/2100 1/3
SAMPLE OUTPUT
1 11/21/2005 IS 1 DAY AFTER
2 11/17/2005 IS 3 DAYS PRIOR
3 SAME DAY
4 11/13/2005 IS 7 DAYS PRIOR
5 OUT OF RANGE
6 12/30/2004 IS 3 DAYS PRIOR
7 1/3/2101 IS 3 DAYS AFTER

ERROR CORRECTION -10PTS
A boolean matrix has the parity property when each row and each column has an even sum, i.e. contains an even number of bits which are set. Here's a 4 x 4 matrix which has the parity property: 
1 0 1 0
0 0 0 0
1 1 1 1
0 1 0 1
The sums of the rows are 2, 0, 4 and 2. The sums of the columns are 2, 2, 2 and 2. 
Your job is to write a program that reads in a matrix and checks if it has the parity property. If not, your program should check if the parity property can be established by changing only one bit. If this is not possible either, the matrix should be classified as corrupt.
INPUT
The input will contain one or more test cases. The first line of each test case contains one integer n (n<100), representing the size of the matrix. On the next n lines, there will be n integers per line. No other integers than 0 and 1 will occur in the matrix. Input will be terminated by a value of 0 for n.
OUTPUT
For each matrix in the input file, print one line. If the matrix already has the parity property, print "OK". If the parity property can be established by changing one bit, print "Change bit (i,j)" where i is the row and j the column of the bit to be changed. Otherwise, print "Corrupt".
SAMPLE INPUT
4
1 0 1 0
0 0 0 0
1 1 1 1
0 1 0 1
4
1 0 1 0
0 0 1 0
1 1 1 1
0 1 0 1
4
1 0 1 0
0 1 1 0
1 1 1 1
0 1 0 1
0
SAMPLE OUTPUT
OK
Change bit (2,3)
Corrupt

FRANCE '98 - 10PTS
Today the first round of the Soccer World Championship in France is coming to an end. 16 countries are remaining now, among which the winner is determined by the following tournament: 

 1 Brazil -----+	

   	       +-- ? --+

 2 Chile ------+       |

		       +-- ? --+

 3 Nigeria ----+       |       |

	       +-- ? --+       |

 4 Denmark ----+	       |

	                       +-- ? --+

 5 Holland ----+	       |       |

	       +-- ? --+       |       |

 6 Yugoslavia -+       |       |       |

		       +-- ? --+       |

 7 Argentina --+       |	       |

	       +-- ? --+	       |

 8 England ----+		       |

				       +-- World Champion

 9 Italy ------+		       |

	       +-- ? --+	       |

10 Norway -----+       |               |

		       +-- ? --+       |

11 France -----+       |       |       |

	       +-- ? --+       |       |

12 Paraguay ---+	       |       |

			       +-- ? --+

13 Germany ----+	       |

	       +-- ? --+       |

14 Mexico -----+       |       |

		       +-- ? --+

15 Romania ----+       |

	       +-- ? --+

16 Croatia ----+

For each possible match A vs. B between these 16 nations, you are given the probability that team A wins against B. This (together with the tournament mode displayed above) is sufficient to compute the probability that a given nation wins the World Cup. For example, if Germany wins against Mexico with 80%, Romania against Croatia with 60%, Germany against Romania with 70% and Germany against Croatia with 90%, then the probability that Germany reaches the semi-finals is 80% * (70% * 60% + 90% * 40%) = 62.4%. 
Your task is to write a program that computes the chances of the 16 nations to become the World Champion '98.

INPUT
The input will contain just one test case. 
The first 16 lines of the input file give the names of the 16 countries, from top to bottom according to the picture given above. 
Next, there will follow a 16 x 16 integer matrix P where element pijgives the probability in percent that country #i defeats country #j in a direct match. Country #i means the i-th country from top to bottom given in the list of countries. In the picture above Brazil is #1 and Germany is #13, so p1,13=55 would mean that in a match between Brazil and Germany, Brazil wins with a probability of 55%. 
Note that matches may not end with a draw, i.e. pij + pji = 100 for all i,j.
OUTPUT
Output 16 lines of the form "XXXXXXXXXX p=Y.YY%", where XXXXXXXXXX is the country's name, left-justified in a field of 10 characters, and Y.YY is their chance in percent to win the cup, written to two decimal places. Use the same order of countries like in the input file.
SAMPLE INPUT
Brazil
Chile
Nigeria
Denmark
Holland
Yugoslavia
Argentina
England
Italy
Norway
France
Paraguay
Germany
Mexico
Romania
Croatia
50 65 50 60 55 50 50 65 45 55 40 55 40 55 50 50 
35 50 35 45 40 35 35 50 30 40 25 40 25 40 35 35 
50 65 50 60 55 50 50 65 45 55 40 55 40 55 50 50 
40 55 40 50 45 40 40 55 35 45 30 45 30 45 40 40 
45 60 45 55 50 45 45 60 40 50 35 50 35 50 45 45 
50 65 50 60 55 50 50 65 45 55 40 55 40 55 50 50 
50 65 50 60 55 50 50 65 45 55 40 55 40 55 50 50 
35 50 35 45 40 35 35 50 30 40 25 40 25 40 35 35 
55 70 55 65 60 55 55 70 50 60 45 60 45 60 55 55 
45 60 45 55 50 45 45 60 40 50 35 50 35 50 45 45 
60 75 60 70 65 60 60 75 55 65 50 65 50 65 60 60 
45 60 45 55 50 45 45 60 40 50 35 50 35 50 45 45 
60 75 60 70 65 60 60 75 55 65 50 65 50 65 60 60 
45 60 45 55 50 45 45 60 40 50 35 50 35 50 45 45 
50 65 50 60 55 50 50 65 45 55 40 55 40 55 50 50 
50 65 50 60 55 50 50 65 45 55 40 55 40 55 50 50
SAMPLE OUTPUT
Brazil     p=8.54%
Chile      p=1.60%
Nigeria    p=8.06%
Denmark    p=2.79%
Holland    p=4.51%
Yugoslavia p=7.50%
Argentina  p=8.38%
England    p=1.56%
Italy      p=9.05%
Norway     p=3.23%
France     p=13.72%
Paraguay   p=3.09%
Germany    p=13.79%
Mexico     p=3.11%
Romania    p=5.53%
Croatia    p=5.53%

HEAVY CARGO - 10PTS
Big Johnsson Trucks Inc. is a company specialized in manufacturing big trucks. Their latest model, the Godzilla V12, is so big that the amount of cargo you can transport with it is never limited by the truck itself. It is only limited by the weight restrictions that apply for the roads along the path you want to drive. 
Given start and destination city, your job is to determine the maximum load of the Godzilla V12 so that there still exists a path between the two specified cities.
INPUT
The input will contain one or more test cases. The first line of each test case will contain two integers: the number of cities n (2<=n<=200) and the number of road segments r (1<=r<=19900) making up the street network. 
Then r lines will follow, each one describing one road segment by naming the two cities connected by the segment and giving the weight limit for trucks that use this segment. Names are not longer than 30 characters and do not contain white-space characters. Weight limits are integers in the range 0 - 10000. Roads can always be travelled in both directions. 
The last line of the test case contains two city names: start and destination. 
Input will be terminated by two values of 0 for n and r.
OUTPUT
For each test case, print three lines: 
-a line saying "Scenario #x" where x is the number of the test case 
-a line saying "y tons" where y is the maximum possible load 
-a blank line
SAMPLE INPUT
4 3
Karlsruhe Stuttgart 100
Stuttgart Ulm 80
Ulm Muenchen 120
Karlsruhe Muenchen
5 5
Karlsruhe Stuttgart 100
Stuttgart Ulm 80
Ulm Muenchen 120
Karlsruhe Hamburg 220
Hamburg Muenchen 170
Muenchen Karlsruhe
0 0
SAMPLE OUTPUT
Scenario #1
80 tons
 
Scenario #2
170 tons

FROG JUMPING - 10PTS
A frog is currently at the point 0 on a coordinate axis Ox. It jumps by the following algorithm: the first jump is a units to the right, the second jump is b units to the left, the third jump is a units to the right, the fourth jump is b units to the left, and so on.
Formally:
-if the frog has jumped an even number of times (before the current jump), it jumps from   its current position x to position x+a;
-otherwise it jumps from its current position x to position x−b.

Your task is to calculate the position of the frog after k jumps.
But... One more thing. You are watching t different frogs so you have to answer t independent queries.
INPUT
The first line of the input contains one integer t (1≤t≤1000) — the number of queries.
Each of the next t lines contain queries (one query per line).
The query is described as three space-separated integers a,b,k (1≤a,b,k≤10^9) — the lengths of two types of jumps and the number of jumps, respectively.
OUTPUT
Print t integers. The i-th integer should be the answer for the i-th query.
SAMPLE INPUT
6
5 2 3
100 1 4
1 10 5
1000000000 1 6
1 1 1000000000
1 1 999999999
SAMPLE OUTPUT
8
198
-17
2999999997
0
1

DISTURBED PEOPLE - 10PTS
There is a house with n flats situated on the main street of Berlatov. Vova is watching this house every night. The house can be represented as an array of n integer numbers a1,a2,…,an, where ai=1 if in the i-th flat the light is on and ai=0 otherwise.
Vova thinks that people in the i-th flats are disturbed and cannot sleep if and only if 1<i<n and ai−1=ai+1=1 and ai=0.
Vova is concerned by the following question: what is the minimum number k such that if people from exactly k pairwise distinct flats will turn off the lights then nobody will be disturbed? Your task is to find this number k.
INPUT
The first line of the input contains one integer n (3≤n≤100) — the number of flats in the house.
The second line of the input contains n integers a1,a2,…,an (ai∈{0,1}), where ai is the state of light in the i-th flat.
OUTPUT
Print only one integer — the minimum number k such that if people from exactly k pairwise distinct flats will turn off the light then nobody will be disturbed.
SAMPLE
INPUT
10
1 1 0 1 1 0 1 0 1 0
OUTPUT
2
INPUT
5
1 1 0 0 0
OUTPUT
0
INPUT
4
1 1 1 1
OUTPUT
0

TRAINSORTING - 15PTS
Erin is an engineer. She drives trains. She also arranges the cars with each train. She prefers to put the cars in decreasing order of weight, with the heaviest car at the front of the train. Unfortunately, sorting train cars is not easy. One cannot simply pick up a car and place it somewhere else. It is impractical to insert a car within an existing train. A car may only be added to the beginning and end of the train. Cars arrive at the train station in a predetermined order. When each car arrives, Erin can add it to the beginning or end of her train, or refuse to add it at all. The resulting train should be as long as possible, but the cars within it must be ordered by weight. Given the weights of the cars in the order in which they arrive, what is the longest train that Erin can make?
INPUT
The first line is the number of test cases to follow. The test cases follow, one after another; the format of each test case is the following:
The first line contains an integer 0 ≤ n ≤ 2000, the number of cars. Each of the following n lines contains a non-negative integer giving the weight of a car. No two cars have the same weight.
OUTPUT
Output a single integer giving the number of cars in the longest train that can be made with the given restrictions.
SAMPLE INPUT
1
3
1
2
3
SAMPLE OUTPUT
3

GOOD ARRAY - 15PTS
Let's call an array good if there is an element in the array that equals to the sum of all other elements. For example, the array a=[1,3,3,7] is good because there is the element a4=7 which equals to the sum 1+3+3.
You are given an array a consisting of n integers. Your task is to print all indices j of this array such that after removing the j-th element from the array it will be good (let's call such indices nice).
For example, if a=[8,3,5,2], the nice indices are 1 and 4:
 -if you remove a1, the array will look like [3,5,2] and it is good;
 -if you remove a4, the array will look like [8,3,5] and it is good.
You have to consider all removals independently, i. e. remove the element, check if the resulting array is good, and return the element into the array.
INPUT
The first line of the input contains one integer n (2≤n≤2*10^5) — the number of elements in the array a.
The second line of the input contains n integers a1,a2,…,an (1≤ai≤10^6) — elements of the array a.
OUTPUT
In the first line print one integer k — the number of indices j of the array a such that after removing the j-th element from the array it will be good (i.e. print the number of the nice indices).
In the second line print k distinct integers j1,j2,…,jk in any order — nice indices of the array a.
If there are no such indices in the array a, just print 0 in the first line and leave the second line empty or do not print it at all.
SAMPLE 
INPUT
5
2 5 1 2 2
OUTPUT
3
4 1 5
INPUT
4
8 3 5 2
OUTPUT
2
1 4 
INPUT
5
2 1 2 4 3
OUTPUT
0

CUTTING OUT - 15PTS
You are given an array s consisting of n integers.
You have to find any array t of length k such that you can cut out maximum number of copies of array t from array s.
Cutting out the copy of t means that for each element ti of array t you have to find ti in s and remove it from s. If for some ti you cannot find such element in s, then you cannot cut out one more copy of t. The both arrays can contain duplicate elements.
For example, if s=[1,2,3,2,4,3,1] and k=3 then one of the possible answers is t=[1,2,3]. This array t can be cut out 2 times.
 -To cut out the first copy of t you can use the elements [1,2−−,3,2,4,3−−,1−−] (use the highlighted elements). After cutting out the first copy of t the array s can look like [1,3,2,4].
 -To cut out the second copy of t you can use the elements [1−−,3−−,2−−,4]. After cutting out the second copy of t the array s will be [4].
Your task is to find such array t that you can cut out the copy of t from s maximum number of times. If there are multiple answers, you may choose any of them.
INPUT
The first line of the input contains two integers n and k (1≤k≤n≤2*10^5) — the number of elements in s and the desired number of elements in t, respectively.
The second line of the input contains exactly n integers s1,s2,…,sn (1≤si≤2*10^5).
OUTPUT
Print k integers — the elements of array t such that you can cut out maximum possible number of copies of this array from s. If there are multiple answers, print any of them. The required array t can contain duplicate elements. All the elements of t (t1,t2,…,tk) should satisfy the following condition: 1≤ti≤2⋅105.
SAMPLE
INPUT
7 3
1 2 3 2 4 3 1
OUTPUT
1 2 3
INPUT
10 4
1 3 1 3 10 3 7 7 12 3
OUTPUT
7 3 1 3
INPUT
15 2
1 2 1 1 1 2 1 1 2 1 2 1 1 1 1
OUTPUT
1 1

THEMATIC CONTEST - 15PTS
Polycarp has prepared n competitive programming problems. The topic of the i-th problem is ai, and some problems' topics may coincide.
Polycarp has to host several thematic contests. All problems in each contest should have the same topic, and all contests should have pairwise distinct topics. He may not use all the problems. It is possible that there are no contests for some topics.
Polycarp wants to host competitions on consecutive days, one contest per day. Polycarp wants to host a set of contests in such a way that:
 -number of problems in each contest is exactly twice as much as in the previous contest (one day ago), the first contest can contain arbitrary number of problems;
 -the total number of problems in all the contests should be maximized.
Your task is to calculate the maximum number of problems in the set of thematic contests. Note, that you should not maximize the number of contests.
INPUT
The first line of the input contains one integer n (1≤n≤2*10^5) — the number of problems Polycarp has prepared.
The second line of the input contains n integers a1,a2,…,an (1≤ai≤10^9) where ai is the topic of the i-th problem.
OUTPUT
Print one integer — the maximum number of problems in the set of thematic contests.
SAMPLE
INPUT
18
2 1 2 10 2 10 10 2 2 1 10 10 10 10 1 1 10 10
OUTPUT
14
INPUT
10
6 6 6 3 6 1000000000 3 3 6 6
OUTPUT
9
INPUT
3
1337 1337 1337
OUTPUT
3

PICTURES WITH KITTENS - 15PTS
The only difference between easy and hard versions is the constraints.
Vova likes pictures with kittens. The news feed in the social network he uses can be represented as an array of n consecutive pictures (with kittens, of course). Vova likes all these pictures, but some are more beautiful than the others: the i-th picture has beauty ai.
Vova wants to repost exactly x pictures in such a way that:
 -each segment of the news feed of at least k consecutive pictures has at least one picture reposted by Vova;
 -the sum of beauty values of reposted pictures is maximum possible.
For example, if k=1 then Vova has to repost all the pictures in the news feed. If k=2 then Vova can skip some pictures, but between every pair of consecutive pictures Vova has to repost at least one of them.
Your task is to calculate the maximum possible sum of values of reposted pictures if Vova follows conditions described above, or say that there is no way to satisfy all conditions.
INPUT
The first line of the input contains three integers n,k and x (1≤k,x≤n≤200) — the number of pictures in the news feed, the minimum length of segment with at least one repost in it and the number of pictures Vova is ready to repost.
The second line of the input contains n integers a1,a2,…,an (1≤ai≤10^9), where ai is the beauty of the i-th picture.
OUTPUT
Print -1 if there is no way to repost some pictures to satisfy all the conditions in the problem statement.
Otherwise print one integer — the maximum sum of values of reposted pictures if Vova follows conditions described in the problem statement.
SAMPLE
INPUT
5 2 3
5 1 3 10 1
OUTPUT
18
INPUT
6 1 5
10 30 30 70 10 10
OUTPUT
-1
INPUT
4 3 1
1 100 1 1
OUTPUT
100

BOOKS QUERIES - 15PTS
You have got a shelf and want to put some books on it.
You are given q queries of three types:
 1. L id — put a book having index id on the shelf to the left from the leftmost existing book;
 2. R id — put a book having index id on the shelf to the right from the rightmost existing book;
 3. ? id — calculate the minimum number of books you need to pop from the left or from the right in such a way that the book with index id will be leftmost or rightmost.
You can assume that the first book you will put can have any position (it does not matter) and queries of type 3 are always valid (it is guaranteed that the book in each such query is already placed). You can also assume that you don't put the same book on the shelf twice, so ids don't repeat in queries of first two types.
Your problem is to answer all the queries of type 3 in order they appear in the input.
Note that after answering the query of type 3 all the books remain on the shelf and the relative order of books does not change.
If you are Python programmer, consider using PyPy instead of Python when you submit your code.
INPUT
The first line of the input contains one integer q (1≤q≤2*10^5) — the number of queries.
Then q lines follow. The i-th line contains the i-th query in format as in the problem statement. It is guaranteed that queries are always valid (for query type 3, it is guaranteed that the book in each such query is already placed, and for other types, it is guaranteed that the book was not placed before).
It is guaranteed that there is at least one query of type 3 in the input.
In each query the constraint 1≤id≤2*10^5 is met.
OUTPUT
Print answers to queries of the type 3 in order they appear in the input.
SAMPLE
INPUT
8
L 1
R 2
R 3
? 2
L 4
? 1
L 5
? 1
OUTPUT
1
1
2
INPUT
10
L 100
R 100000
R 123
L 101
? 123
L 10
R 115
? 100
R 110
? 115
OUTPUT
0
2
1

BOXES PACKING - 15PTS
Maksim has n objects and m boxes, each box has size exactly k. Objects are numbered from 1 to n in order from left to right, the size of the i-th object is ai.
Maksim wants to pack his objects into the boxes and he will pack objects by the following algorithm: he takes one of the empty boxes he has, goes from left to right through the objects, and if the i-th object fits in the current box (the remaining size of the box is greater than or equal to ai), he puts it in the box, and the remaining size of the box decreases by ai. Otherwise he takes the new empty box and continues the process above. If he has no empty boxes and there is at least one object not in some box then Maksim cannot pack the chosen set of objects.
Maksim wants to know the maximum number of objects he can pack by the algorithm above. To reach this target, he will throw out the leftmost object from the set until the remaining set of objects can be packed in boxes he has. Your task is to say the maximum number of objects Maksim can pack in boxes he has.
Each time when Maksim tries to pack the objects into the boxes, he will make empty all the boxes he has before do it (and the relative order of the remaining set of objects will not change).
INPUT
The first line of the input contains three integers n, m, k (1≤n,m≤2*10^5, 1≤k≤10^9) — the number of objects, the number of boxes and the size of each box.
The second line of the input contains n integers a1,a2,…,an (1≤ai≤k), where ai is the size of the i-th object.
OUTPUT
Print the maximum number of objects Maksim can pack using the algorithm described in the problem statement.
SAMPLE
INPUT
5 2 6
5 2 1 4 2
OUTPUT
4
INPUT
5 1 4
4 2 3 4 1
OUTPUT
1
INPUT
5 3 3
1 2 3 1 1
OUTPUT
5

BINARY NUMBERS AND SUM - 15PTS
You are given two huge binary integer numbers a and b of lengths n and m respectively. You will repeat the following process: if b>0, then add to the answer the value a & b and divide b by 2 rounding down (i.e. remove the last digit of b), and repeat the process again, otherwise stop the process.
The value a & b means bitwise AND of a and b. Your task is to calculate the answer modulo 998244353.
Note that you should add the value a & b to the answer in decimal notation, not in binary. So your task is to calculate the answer in decimal notation. For example, if a=10102 (1010) and b=10002 (810), then the value a & b will be equal to 8, not to 1000.
INPUT
The first line of the input contains two integers n and m (1≤n,m≤2*10^5) — the length of a and the length of b correspondingly.
The second line of the input contains one huge integer a. It is guaranteed that this number consists of exactly n zeroes and ones and the first digit is always 1.
The third line of the input contains one huge integer b. It is guaranteed that this number consists of exactly m zeroes and ones and the first digit is always 1.
OUTPUT
Print the answer to this problem in decimal notation modulo 998244353.
SAMPLE
INPUT
4 4
1010
1101
OUTPUT
12
INPUT
4 5
1001
10101
OUTPUT
11

SUM AND PRODUCT - 20PTS
For a sequence of N integers A 1, A 2, ... , A N, we can calculate their sum S and product P easily. With given N, S and P, can you find out the sequence A 1, A 2, ... , A N?
INPUT
The input only contains a line with three integers N, S and P. Here N is positive and not more than 1000000, and the absolute values of S and P do not exceed 150000000.
OUTPUT
Just output "No solution" if there is no such sequence, or you may output any solution with N integers A 1, A 2, ... , A N, separated by just one space.
SAMPLE
INPUT
2 4 3
OUTPUT
1 3
INPUT
4 4 2
OUTPUT
No solution

CHOPSTICKS - 20PTS
In China, people use a pair fo chopsticks to get food on the table, but Mr. L is a bit differetn. He uses a set of three chopsticks - one pair, plus an EXTRA long chopstick to get some big food by piercing it through the food. As you may guess, the length of the two shorter chopsticks should be as close as possible, but the length of the extra one is not important, as long as it’s the longest. To make things clearer, for the set of chopsticks with lengths A, B, C (A ≤ B ≤ C), (A − B)2 is called the “badness” of the set.
It’s December 2nd, Mr.L’s birthday! He invited K people to join his birthday party, and would like to introduce his way of using chopsticks. So, he should prepare K + 8 sets of chopsticks(for himself, his wife, his little son, little daughter, his mother, father, mother-in-law, father-in-law, and K other guests). But Mr.L suddenly discovered that his chopsticks are of quite different lengths! He should find a way of composing the K + 8 sets, so that the total badness of all the sets is minimized.
INPUT
The first line in the input contains a single integer T, indicating the number of test cases (1 ≤ T ≤ 20). Each test case begins with two integers K, N (0 ≤ K ≤ 1000, 3K + 24 ≤ N ≤ 5000), the number of guests and the number of chopsticks.
There are N positive integers Li on the next line in non–decreasing order indicating the lengths of the chopsticks (1 ≤ Li ≤ 32000).
OUTPUT
For each test case in the input, print a line containing the minimal total badness of all the sets.
SAMPLE INPUT
1
1 40
1 8 10 16 19 22 27 33 36 40 47 52 56 61 63 71 72 75 81 81 84 88 96 98
103 110 113 118 124 128 129 134 134 139 148 157 157 160 162 164
SAMPLE OUTPUT
23

PICTURES WITH KITTENS - 20PTS
The only difference between easy and hard versions is the constraints.
Vova likes pictures with kittens. The news feed in the social network he uses can be represented as an array of n consecutive pictures (with kittens, of course). Vova likes all these pictures, but some are more beautiful than the others: the i-th picture has beauty ai.
Vova wants to repost exactly x pictures in such a way that:
 -each segment of the news feed of at least k consecutive pictures has at least one picture reposted by Vova;
 -the sum of beauty values of reposted pictures is maximum possible.
For example, if k=1 then Vova has to repost all the pictures in the news feed. If k=2 then Vova can skip some pictures, but between every pair of consecutive pictures Vova has to repost at least one of them.
Your task is to calculate the maximum possible sum of values of reposted pictures if Vova follows conditions described above, or say that there is no way to satisfy all conditions.
INPUT
The first line of the input contains three integers n,k and x (1≤k,x≤n≤5000) — the number of pictures in the news feed, the minimum length of segment with at least one repost in it and the number of pictures Vova is ready to repost.
The second line of the input contains n integers a1,a2,…,an (1≤ai≤10^9), where ai is the beauty of the i-th picture.
OUTPUT
Print -1 if there is no way to repost some pictures to satisfy all the conditions in the problem statement.
Otherwise print one integer — the maximum sum of values of reposted pictures if Vova follows conditions described in the problem statement.
SAMPLE
INPUT
5 2 3
5 1 3 10 1
OUTPUT
18
INPUT
6 1 5
10 30 30 70 10 10
OUTPUT
-1
INPUT
4 3 1
1 100 1 1
OUTPUT
100

YET ANOTHER 2D WALKING - 20PTS
Maksim walks on a Cartesian plane. Initially, he stands at the point (0,0) and in one move he can go to any of four adjacent points (left, right, up, down). For example, if Maksim is currently at the point (0,0), he can go to any of the following points in one move:
 -(1,0);
 -(0,1);
 -(−1,0);
 -(0,−1).
There are also n distinct key points at this plane. The i-th point is pi=(xi,yi). It is guaranteed that 0≤xi and 0≤yi and there is no key point (0,0).
Let the first level points be such points that max(xi,yi)=1, the second level points be such points that max(xi,yi)=2 and so on. Maksim wants to visit all the key points. But he shouldn't visit points of level i+1 if he does not visit all the points of level i. He starts visiting the points from the minimum level of point from the given set.
The distance between two points (x1,y1) and (x2,y2) is |x1−x2|+|y1−y2| where |v| is the absolute value of v.
Maksim wants to visit all the key points in such a way that the total distance he walks will be minimum possible. Your task is to find this distance.
If you are Python programmer, consider using PyPy instead of Python when you submit your code.
INPUT
The first line of the input contains one integer n (1≤n≤2*10^5) — the number of key points.
Each of the next n lines contains two integers xi, yi (0≤xi,yi≤10^9) — x-coordinate of the key point pi and y-coordinate of the key point pi. It is guaranteed that all the points are distinct and the point (0,0) is not in this set.
OUTPUT
Print one integer — the minimum possible total distance Maksim has to travel if he needs to visit all key points in a way described above.
SAMPLE
INPUT
8
2 2
1 4
2 3
3 1
3 4
1 1
4 3
1 2
OUTPUT
15
INPUT
5
2 1
1 0
2 0
3 2
0 3
OUTPUT
9