A
You are given a number 1 ≤ N ≤ 50. Every ticket has its 2 N-digit number. We call a ticket lucky, if the sum of its first N digits is equal to the sum of its last N digits. You are also given the sum of ALL digits in the number. Your task is to count an amount of lucky numbers, having the specified sum of ALL digits.
INPUT
Two space-separated numbers: N and S. Here S is the sum of all digits. Assume that 0 ≤ S ≤ 1000.
OUTPUT
The amount of lucky tickets.
SAMPLE INPUT
2 2
SAMPLE OUTPUT
4


B
This problem is the same as “War Games 2” but with bigger limitations.
During the latest war games the Minister of Defense of the Soviet Federation comrade Ivanov had a good chance to make sure personally, that an alertness of the Soviet Army under his command is just brilliant. But there was a thing, that continued to worry him. Being an outstanding commander, he realized, that only physical conditions of the soldiers were demonstrated. So the time came to organize one more war games and examine their mental capacity.
General Rascal was appointed to be responsible for the war games again. The general donated the allocated funds to the poor and went to bed free-hearted. In his dream, the tactics manual appeared to him and described a scheme, that allows organizing the war games absolutely free of charge.
In accordance with this scheme, the war games are divided into N phases; and N soldiers, successively numbered from 1 to N, are marching round a circle one after another, i.e. the first follows the second, the second follows the third, ..., the ( N−1)-th follows the N-th, and the N-th follows the first. At each phase, a single soldier leaves the circle and goes to clean the WC, while the others continue to march. At some phase, the circle is left by a soldier, who is marching K positions before the one, who left the circle at the previous phase. A soldier, whose number is K, leaves the circle at the first phase.
Surely, Mr. Rascal cherished no hope about his soldiers’ abilities to determine an order of leaving the circle. "These fools can not even paint the grass properly", he sniffed scornfully and went to sergeant Filcher for an assistance.
INPUT
The only line contains the integer numbers N (1 ≤ N ≤ 1.1 * 10^6) and K (1 ≤ K ≤ N).
OUTPUT
Since the answer (the numbers of soldiers as they leave the circle) is sometimes too large, you should output only one integer: xor of the numbers | i − s i| for each i from 1 to N, where s i is the number of the soldier, which has lived the circle on the i-th step.
SAMPLE INPUT
5 3
SAMPLE OUTPUT
2


C
Two students are playing the following game. There are 2· n points on the plane, given with their coordinates ( xi,  yi). Each move player paints the point with his own color (first with white, second with black). The first student makes odd moves, second student makes even moves. When all points are painted (each student made n moves), the game finishes. Each student gets amount of points (real number) that equals to the sum of all distances among pairs of points, colored with his color. Student who get more points becomes a winner. The students play optimally. Find and print the difference between points amount of winner and looser.
INPUT
Contains multiple test cases. The first line of each case contains positive integer number n ( n ≤ 500). Next 2· n lines contain points' coordinates ( x 1, y 1), ( x 2, y 2), …, ( x 2n, y 2n).
OUTPUT
For each test case output the difference between the points of winner and looser. Output the difference with three digits after decimal point.
SAMPLE INPUT
2
0 0
0 1
1 0
1 1
2
0 0
1 0
0 3
1 5
SAMPLE OUTPUT
0.000
1.937


D
There is a certain amount of night guards that are available to protect the local junkyard from possible junk robberies. These guards need to be scheduled in pairs so that each pair guards in a different night. The junkyard CEO ordered you to write a program which given the guards characteristics determines the maximum amount of scheduled guards (the rest will be fired). Please note that each guard can be scheduled with only one of his colleagues and no guard can work alone.
INPUT
The first line of the input contains one number N ≤ 222 which is a number of night guards. Unlimited number of lines consisting of unordered pairs ( i,  j) follow, each such pair means that guard # i and guard # j can work together, because it is possible to find uniforms that suit both of them (The junkyard uses different parts of uniforms for different guards i.e. helmets, pants, jackets. It is impossible to put small helmet on a guard with a big head or big shoes on guard with small feet). The input ends with Eof.
OUTPUT
You should output one possible optimal assignment. On the first line of the output write the even number C, the amount of scheduled guards. Then output C/2 lines, each containing 2 integers ( i,  j) that denote that i and j will work together.
SAMPLE INPUT
3
1 2
2 3
1 3
SAMPLE OUTPUT
2
1 2


E
The fundamental theorem of arithmetic states that every integer greater than 1 can be uniquely represented as a product of one or more primes. While unique, several arrangements of the prime factors may be possible. For example:
 -10 = 2 * 5 = 5 * 2
 -20 = 2 * 2 * 5 = 2 * 5 * 2 = 5 * 2 * 2
Let f(k) be the number of different arrangements of the prime factors of k. So f(10) = 2 and f(20) = 3.
Given a positive number n, there always exists at least one number k such that f(k) = n. We want to know the smallest such k.
INPUT
The input consists of at most 1000 test cases, each on a separate line. Each test case is a positive integer n < 2^63.
OUTPUT
For each test case, display its number n and the smallest number k > 1 such that f(k) = n. The numbers in the input are chosen such that k < 2^63.
SAMPLE INPUT
1
2
3
105
SAMPLE OUTPUT
1 2
2 6
3 12
105 720


G
The cows in farmer John's herd are numbered and branded with consecutive integers from 1 to N (1 <= N <= 10,000,000). When the cows come to the barn for milking, they always come in sequential order from 1 to N. 
Farmer John, who majored in mathematics in college and loves numbers, often looks for patterns. He has noticed that when he has exactly 15 cows in his herd, there are precisely four ways that the numbers on any set of one or more consecutive cows can add up to 15 (the same as the total number of cows). They are: 15, 7+8, 4+5+6, and 1+2+3+4+5. 
When the number of cows in the herd is 10, the number of ways he can sum consecutive cows and get 10 drops to 2: namely 1+2+3+4 and 10. 
Write a program that will compute the number of ways farmer John can sum the numbers on consecutive cows to equal N. Do not use precomputation to solve this problem.
INPUT
* Line 1: A single integer: N 
OUTPUT
* Line 1: A single integer that is the number of ways consecutive cow brands can sum to N. 
SAMPLE INPUT
15
SAMPLE OUTPUT
4


H
The classic Two Glass Balls brain-teaser is often posed as: 
"Given two identical glass spheres, you would like to determine the lowest floor in a 100-story building from which they will break when dropped. Assume the spheres are undamaged when dropped below this point. What is the strategy that will minimize the worst-case scenario for number of drops?"
Suppose that we had only one ball. We'd have to drop from each floor from 1 to 100 in sequence, requiring 100 drops in the worst case. 
Now consider the case where we have two balls. Suppose we drop the first ball from floor n. If it breaks we're in the case where we have one ball remaining and we need to drop from floors 1 to n-1 in sequence, yielding n drops in the worst case (the first ball is dropped once, the second at most n-1 times). However, if it does not break when dropped from floor n, we have reduced the problem to dropping from floors n+1 to 100. In either case we must keep in mind that we've already used one drop. So the minimum number of drops, in the worst case, is the minimum over all n. 
You will write a program to determine the minimum number of drops required, in the worst case, given B balls and an M-story building.
INPUT
The first line of input contains a single integer P, (1 ≤ P ≤ 1000), which is the number of data sets that follow. Each data set consists of a single line containing three(3) decimal integer values: the problem number, followed by a space, followed by the number of balls B, (1 ≤ B ≤ 50), followed by a space and the number of floors in the building M, (1 ≤ M ≤ 1000).
OUTPUT
For each data set, generate one line of output with the following values: The data set number as a decimal integer, a space, and the minimum number of drops needed for the corresponding values of B and M.
SAMPLE INPUT
4 
1 2 10 
2 2 100 
3 2 300 
4 25 900
SAMPLE OUTPUT
1 4
2 14
3 24
4 10